<record><leader>00000cas a2200000 a 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">33600607</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">951120d18931958fluwr ne      0   a0eng c</controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010"><subfield code="a">sn 95047324 </subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">FUG</subfield><subfield code="b">eng</subfield><subfield code="c">FUG</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCQ</subfield><subfield code="d">DLC</subfield><subfield code="d">UPM</subfield><subfield code="d">DLC</subfield><subfield code="d">FUG</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCQ</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCF</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCO</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="022"><subfield code="a">1940-9796</subfield><subfield code="l">1940-9796</subfield><subfield code="2">1</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="029"><subfield code="a">AU@</subfield><subfield code="b">000012176060</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042"><subfield code="a">pcc</subfield><subfield code="a">nsdp</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="043"><subfield code="a">n-us-fl</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050"><subfield code="a">Newspaper</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="222"><subfield code="a">The Punta Gorda herald</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="245"><subfield code="a">The Punta Gorda herald.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2="3" tag="246"><subfield code="a">Herald</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="260"><subfield code="a">Punta Gorda, Fla. :</subfield><subfield code="b">A.P. Jordan,</subfield><subfield code="c">-1958.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">v.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="310"><subfield code="a">Weekly</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="362"><subfield code="a">Began on Feb. 17, 1893.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="362"><subfield code="a">-v. 66, no. 48 (Dec. 4, 1958).</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">Paul K. Garrett, editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="520"><subfield code="a">The Punta Gorda (FL) Herald [LCCN: sn95047324] covered such lively events as rum running, other smuggling activities, and lawlessness in general. Among news items of note is a visit by Carry Nation (1846-1911), a self-described "bulldog" activist for Prohibition. Nation came to Punta Gorda to counter the influence of a favorite son, General Albert W. Gilchrist. General Gilchrist, for whom Gilchrist County, Florida is named, favored the availability of alcohol. Her visit in 1908 had been orchestrated by Neva Chase Child, publisher of the Champion [LCCN sn95047227] in nearby Arcadia, Florida. In its June 18, 1908 issue, the Punta Gorda Herald reported that "Only one paper in the entire state made any derogatory charge or insinuation against the private character of General Gilchrist and that paper is edited by a woman. We once heard an imminent Kentucky preacher say that a woman cannot tell the truth, and yet he had never read this paper that slandered Gilchrist and we, therefore, cannot imagine why he made the allegation." This rhetoric was thick with dry humor as the Punta Gorda Herald generally favored the General. Gilchrist, a hero of the Spanish-American war, was elected to the office of Governor of the State of Florida in November 1908, taking office in 1909. The Punta Gorda Herald was founded by Robert Kirby Seward in 1893 and published weekly during its early history. The Punta Gorda Herald literally watched the city of Punta Gorda grow up, starting with the arrival of the Florida Southern Railway. At that time Punta Gorda, now in Charlotte County (FL) was still part of DeSoto County (FL). Punta Gorda was first settled in 1882 and incorporated in 1900. Seward's press was foot-operated and produced two pages that were smaller than today's newspapers. Under the masthead was the slogan, "In God We Trust, All Others Cash." One paper cost five cents while an annual subscription was a dollar. The "inevitable" fire, they were so common in Florida journalism history, in November of 1895 destroyed the print shop. The printing press was too large and cumbersome to move, so Seward was left with only a few cases of type and a small cabinet. After much encouragement and the financial backing of his brother-in-law, James Sandlin, and other businessmen, Seward rebuilt on the same site. He bought new equipment and boasted later that he never again missed publication. Seward sold the newspaper to Adrian Pettus Jordan in 1901. Prior to buying the Punta Gorda Herald, Jordan was known for his attacks on a railroad company that was acquiring land grants dishonestly. Then editor of the Wild Wood (FL) Orange Leaf [LCCN: sn97027627] in Sumter County (FL), Jordan's crusade brought about the state legislature's intervention into the affair. Jordan was also instrumental in getting General Gilchrist elected as State Representative and later Governor of Florida. There was even a failed assassination attempt on Jordan's life. He died in 1928 but his son, Adrian Crenshaw Jordan, assumed ownership, which he maintained until 1951. In 1958, the title changed to the simpler form, the Herald [LCCN: sn95047325]. Today (ca. 2008), it appears that the Herald has been succeeded by the Charlotte (FL) Sun-Herald [LCCN sn 91002725]. The Charlotte Sun-Herald website (ca. 2008) indicates that the Punta Gorda Herald has been published inside the Charlotte Sun-Herald on Wednesdays since 1991 when both papers were acquired by the Sun Coast Media Group, an independent Florida newspaper group. --E. Kesse, University of Florida Digital Library Center.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="530"><subfield code="a">Archived issues are available in digital format as part of the Library of Congress Chronicling America online collection.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="588"><subfield code="a">Description based on: Vol. 10, no. 1 (Jan. 10, 1902).</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="651"><subfield code="a">Punta Gorda (Fla.)</subfield><subfield code="v">Newspapers.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="651"><subfield code="a">Charlotte County (Fla.)</subfield><subfield code="v">Newspapers.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="655"><subfield code="a">Newspapers.</subfield><subfield code="2">fast</subfield><subfield code="0">(OCoLC)fst01423814</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="651"><subfield code="a">Florida</subfield><subfield code="z">Charlotte County.</subfield><subfield code="2">fast</subfield><subfield code="0">(OCoLC)fst01217561</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="651"><subfield code="a">Florida</subfield><subfield code="z">Punta Gorda.</subfield><subfield code="2">fast</subfield><subfield code="0">(OCoLC)fst01217542</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="752"><subfield code="a">United States</subfield><subfield code="b">Florida</subfield><subfield code="c">Charlotte</subfield><subfield code="d">Punta Gorda.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="8" tag="776"><subfield code="i">Online version:</subfield><subfield code="t">Punta Gorda herald (Online)</subfield><subfield code="w">(DLC)  2007264071</subfield><subfield code="w">(OCoLC)182985783</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="785"><subfield code="t">Herald (Punta Gorda, Fla.)</subfield><subfield code="w">(DLC)sn 95047325</subfield><subfield code="w">(OCoLC)33600609</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="850"><subfield code="a">DLC</subfield><subfield code="a">FU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="4" ind2="1" tag="856"><subfield code="u">http://www.loc.gov/chroniclingamerica/lccn/sn95047324/issues</subfield></datafield></record>